# **Noor Ismot Ara**

Portfolio: <u>BugHunterNoor.se</u> | LinkedIn: <u>Noor.Ismot</u> | Github: <u>Noor-Ismot</u> Email: ara.noor.ismot@gmail.com | Mobile: 0767509527 |

Address: Stjärngatan 8A, 451 51 Uddevalla |

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Hi there! I'm Noor Ismot Ara, ISTOB certified and a dedicated Software Quality Assurance and Tester with 3.5 years of experience. I've worked on 20+ projects for a global pharmaceutical company, adhering to all test standards.

Skilled in creating Manual and Automation testing, test plans, executing tests, and overseeing pre/post-release activities. My commitment to excellence and collaboration with diverse teams ensures **meeting deadlines** and successful project delivery.

Currently working at SustainLab, integrating my software testing proficiency with data analytics technology. Outside of work, I enjoy listening to tech podcasts, writing articles on SQA, and traveling. I'm seeking to lead a challenging career and contribute to a progressive company's goals while enhancing my skills and knowledge.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

SustainLab Stockholm, Sweden January 2024 - Present

Software Quality Assurance and Test Intern

Performing all possible testing types on product

- Recording, reporting, and tracking defects throughout testing and managing them through JIRA
- Maintaining the bug life cycle
- Prepare documentation related to testing

# **Brain Station-23 Ltd**

SQA Engineer

Dhaka, Bangladesh

July 2019 - November 2022

- Conducted feature testing, sanity, regression, functional, UI and Automation testing for both web and mobile applications.
- Communicated and Collaborated with other teams (Developers, content factory, business, operation) to accomplish any project.
- Recording, reporting, and tracking defects throughout testing and managing them through JIRA
- Involved in Software Life Cycle (SLC) Documentation using Confluence
- Provided walkthroughs of the application to the client
- Provided support for post-release testing activities
- Led multiple projects with my teammates for test activities

# **Projects**

- A Comprehensive Case study of a Tested global web application
- E-commerce Website Cypress Automation Test
- Programming Projects
- Mobile Application Test Case Sample

#### **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

- Web and Mobile application manual and Automation testing with Cypress
- JIRA, Trello, Confluence, GitHub
- Programming language: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python, SQL
- Ability to perform tasks efficiently within the deadline
- Familiarity with accessibility testing and security testing (with burp tool)

# **EDUCATION**

East West University

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science & Engineering

Dhaka, Bangladesh

2014 - 2018

Viqarunnisa Noon College
Secondary & Higher Secondary Certificate (Science)

Dhaka, Bangladesh 2001-2013

# **VOLUNTARY WORK**

 General Committee Member at Youth School for Social Entrepreneurs (YSSE). (2019 January – 2019 May)

#### **RESEARCH PAPERS**

- Thesis on "Anomaly Based Intrusion Detection Using Dempster's Rule of Combination"
- Enthusiasm Against Cyber-Bullying: Intensity of Technical Knowledge and Analysis.
- Mining of Educational Dataset to Analyze Students' Academic Performance

**URL**: Research Papers

# Languages:

Bengali (Mother language), English (Fluent), Urdu (Fluent), Hindi (Fluent), Swedish (Beginner)

Interests: Tech podcast, Nature Videography, Budgies, Traveling.